流血不止
Uncontrollable bleeding.
酸中毒
Acidosis.
體溫下降
Cold.
我們都知道這意味著什麼
We all know what the combination means
飽和信號值低
我們把它叫做致死三聯徵
We call it the trait of death.
到這已經無力迴天了
The point of no return.
我們幾個月都在討論要孩子的事
We've been talking about having another baby for months!
我們很激動  我們還在討論名字
We were excited! we were discussing freaking names!
你為什麼這麼做  就為了讓我燃起希望嗎
Why would you do that -- just to get my hopes up?
你簡直在無中生有
You're attacking me for something
我根本沒說過什麼
that I never even said!
你還需要說麼
you didn't have to say anything!
你的所作所為"說"得很清楚
It's clear from everything
你不想要孩子
that you do that you don't want this.
為什麼你要去當研究員
Why start training all over again?
你已經是個很棒的兒科醫生了
You're an amazing pediatric surgeon.
家長們不遠千里來這讓你給他們孩子做手術
People cross the country just to have you operate on their kids.
我再說最後一次
For the last time,
這個進修項目能讓我的工作更上一層
This fellowship is advancing my career, which is --
但對這個家庭卻沒有任何好處
Which is not advancing this family!
此時在手術室中
It's the moment in the O.R.
你要開始控制損傷
when you turn to damage control.
凱麗  我打斷你一下
Callie, actually, if I could stop you there,
我想聽聽亞利桑那下面要說什麼
I'm interested to hear the rest of Arizona's sentence.
亞利桑那  你剛才要說什麼
Arizona, you were going to say...?
你停下來
You stop.
退後一步
You step back.
身心放鬆  想想是否能
You let the body rest and see if you can find a solution...
解決這些起於蕭墻的禍亂
to the chaos that's happening inside.
-考特尼  你做得很好  -夾鉗
- Courtney, you're doing great. - Clamp.
她沒事吧  快告訴我她沒事
Is she okay? Tell me she's okay.
當然啊  她漂亮極了
Are you kidding? She's absolutely beautiful.
-是嗎  羅賓斯  -她太漂亮了
- Isn't that right, Robbins? - She's so beautiful.
我們要給她做檢查  然後給她吸氧
We're just gonna check her out and get her a little oxygen.
紗墊
Lap pads.
-胎盤  羅賓斯  -我知道了
- All right, the placenta, Robbins. - Yeah, I got it.
阿歷克斯  她的血氧飽和度如何
Uh, hey, Alex, how are her sats?
低於90  但我在手控供氧  她在恢復
Below 90, but improving with bagging.
很好  給她做好準備轉移
All right, let's get her ready to go.
羅賓斯  嬰兒已經不是你的病人了
Robbins, the baby is no longer your patient.
集中注意力到這裡
Pay attention here.
亞利桑那  你準備好了嗎
Arizona, you ready?
我喜歡你在和病人交流的時候
I love when you talk to a patient
專心全意地  就仿佛他們是唯一的存在
And it's like they're the only person in the whole world.
我喜歡當你研究掃描結果時
I love, um, you bite your lip just a teeny bit --
輕咬自己的嘴脣  這動作很細微
It's barely noticeable -- when you study scans,
但我覺得很性感
and I find it really sexy.
我喜歡你晚上給索菲亞念書
I love when you do the voices
逗她發笑時候的聲音
when you read to Sofia at night and make her laugh
我喜歡聽那個聲音  一整天都聽不厭
and I could listen to that sound all day...
聽一輩子也不會
for the rest of my life.
我還喜歡你睡覺時的笑容
And you smile when you sleep --
很大  特別大的笑容
like, big, like, crazy-big.
我喜歡每早一睜眼
And I love that when I wake up,
就看到你笑
that's the first thing I see.
我還喜歡...
Uh, and I love --
為什麼  為什麼你  天哪
See, why -- why don't you just -- god.
凱麗  你想不想說一下
Callie, do you want to talk about
你對這些有什麼要說的
how Arizona's words make you feel?
就是  我就是  我
Um, well, it's just -- I just -- I -- I --
如果你能偶爾說給我聽就好了
If you'd say this stuff out loud once in a while.
那也得你給我機會說啊
I would if you'd let me.
-你這是什麼意思  -我剛才就在說啊
- Wait, what? - I was just saying them right now,
然後你就打斷我了
and then you cut me off,
我是說你一直都在替我說話
I mean, you're too busy trying to speak for me --
好吧  記得我們之前說過的
Okay, remember the language
彼此之間談話的用詞
we talked about using with each other.
我覺得你一直在...
I feel that you're always cutting --
我覺得你一直在指責我...
Well, I feel that you're constantly accusing me of this --
我覺得你剛才又打斷我了
I feel that you just did that again.
-她剛才又打斷我了  -再來一次
- She just did it again! - let's try again.
凱麗  我覺得
Callie, I feel, uh,
你應該先進行一期修補
that you should go with a primary repair.
我覺得主動脈的缺口太大了
Eh, I feel the artery's missing too large a piece.
我們要做一個插入移植
We'll do an interposition graft.
你術前還跟我意見一致呢
W-- you agreed with me in pre-op.
對  但我進來看見缺口大小後
Yeah, well, I changed my mind once I got in here
我改變想法了
and saw the extent of the defect.
我把出血點結紮了
Um, finished ligating the bleeders,
我們這裡都完成了
so we're all set up here.
對  我沒看見骨折碎片  托瑞斯醫生
Yeah, and I don't see any more bone fragments, Dr. Torres, so --
你竟然理都不理我的醫學建議
When you so quickly disregard my medical opinion,
我也是兒科醫生好麼
it makes me feel like you forget that I'm a pediatric surgeon
我知道植入移植
who knows that interpositional grafts
會在兒童中引起併發症
can cause complications in children.
好吧  你在手術室中質疑我
Well, when you question me in the O.R.,
讓我覺得你認為我無法勝任我的工作
it makes me feel like you don't think I can do my job.
我們用聚四氟乙烯材料移植  威爾遜
We'll use a PTFE graft, Wilson.
用大隱隱靜脈  威爾遜
Use the great saphenous vein, Wilson.
我們不需要任何合成材料
We don't need any synthetic materials.
好吧  那就把這孩子的腿切開
Okay, fine, cut into the kid's leg.
這跟腿沒有關係
It's not about the leg
這從來都...這比腿的事情早得多
it was never about the -- it goes way before the leg.
4年前  我得到了千載難逢的一筆資助
Four years ago, I received the grant of a lifetime.
讓我能去非洲的診所工作
Going to Africa, working in that clinic --
我想都沒想過能有那個機會
That was an opportunity that I never thought that I would get.
於是你就去了  完成你的夢想
You followed your dream. You went.
但你應該跟我一起去的
But you were supposed to go with me,
然後你變得很痛苦
and you were miserable
而且大家都知道
and letting everyone know about it.
然後我去了  你沒去
And so I went. I went without you,
最後為了你我回來了
And then I came back -- for you.
我回來是為了你
I came back for you.
-但我回來的時候  你呢  -懷孕了
- And when I came back, you were -- - Pregnant?
我是雙性戀
I'm bisexual.
我男女都喜歡  這嚇壞她了
I'm attracted to both men and women, and it freaks her out.
對  我和馬克睡了  然後懷孕了
Yes, I slept with Mark. I got pregnant.
我懷孕了  然後呢
I was pregnant. And?
我沒有時間去想清楚
And I had no time to process it.
我完全愛上你了
I was so in love with you,
我無論如何就想和你在一起
I just wanted to be with you, no matter what.
如果能和你在一起
And I-if in order to be with you --
如果你下面說的跟我想的一樣
If you're about to say what I think you're about to say --
讓我繼續說  凱麗
Let me get a word in, Callie!
我強迫你接受了孩子
I trapped you into a kid,
一個你本不想要的孩子  而你現在痛苦了
a kid you never wanted, and now you're stuck.
你沒權利說
Don't you ever say
我不愛我的孩子  我後悔有孩子
that I don't love my child or that I regret my child!
我後悔的是你替我做了決定
I regret that you made a decision for me!
你做了所有的決定
You make all the choices!
而我每次想要為自己做一次決定
And every time that I try to make a decision for myself,
你就會讓我覺得
it's like you make me feel like
我成了世界上最無恥自私的人
the worst, most selfish person in the whole world!
抱歉  當你出軌的時候
I'm sorry. Did I make you feel selfish
是我讓你覺得自私了嗎
when you decided to sleep with another woman?
-我真是抱歉啊  -這不是我的意思
- I'm so sorry. - That's not what I meant,
你知道我說的不是這個意思
and you know that's not what I meant.
我是說每一次我試圖為自己做點事
I meant that anytime that I try and do something for myself,
你...你...
you -- you -- j--
凱麗  這次會談還沒結束
Callie, the session's not done yet.
我覺得已經結束了
It feels pretty done.
不行
No!
這是我聽過最蠢的想法
That's the stupidest idea I've ever heard.
這不是個蠢主意  她不是說"蠢"
It is not a stupid idea. She didn't mean "stupid."
她剛剛用的就是這個字
She just said the word "stupid," so --
你們剛才說要把我的
You're talking about spending
一大部分的研究基金用於
a large portion of my grant money
複雜的分期面部重建手術上
on a complicated staged facial reconstruction
而且只是一個病人
for one patient.
那你是打算拒絕這個病人嗎
So, what, you want to just reject him?
不  我們要找一個沒有這麼蠢的辦法
No, we find a way to help him that's less stupid!
好吧  我去吃午飯
Okay, I'm gonna grab lunch.
亨特  一會去找我
Hunt, find me later.
發生什麼事了
What's going on, huh?
我一直不停地付出  付出  付出
It's just I keep giving and giving and giving.
凱麗  你付出的東西都是我不想要的
You're giving me things I didn't ask for, Callie.
這一點都不對
That is not true!
我所做的一切都是你要求我的
All I've done is everything that you've asked me to do.
你要我墜機事件後不離開你  我沒有
You asked me to not leave you after the plane crash. I didn't.
你要我在你出軌後不離開你  我沒有
You wanted me to stay after you cheated on me. I did.
然後你想要一棟房子  我們也買了
Then you wanted a house. We got it.
我為你做了一切  亞利桑那
I do everything for you, Arizona,
-因為我愛你  -我也愛你
- because I love you. - I love you, too!
但現在我們在這裡  我有想要的
Well, and now we're here, and I want something,
但你卻不給我  你卻不願意給我
and you can't give it to me. You won't give it to me.
我從來沒說過我不想要孩子
I never said that I didn't want a baby!
我們在這裡的所有原因
The whole reason that we're here
都是因為你和你想要的
is because of you and what you want.
我在試圖滿足你的要求
I am trying to give you what you want,
但你卻讓我越來越難以做到
but you make it so hard.
為什麼你一點都不願意奉獻
Why can't you commit to anything?
我已經將過去的五年都獻給了你
I've committed the past five years of my life to you.
我們完全沒有進展
We're...not getting anywhere.
又回到原點了
We've circled right back to where we started.
還是重來過比較好
It may be time to hit the reset button.
行  重來吧
Great. Let's -- let's reset.
怎麼重來
How?
你們有沒有想過分開一段時間
Have you ever considered spending some time apart?
大家冷靜一下其實可以
Because a break can actually --
你是說分居嗎  不行
You mean a separation? No.
我們是在輓救婚姻  不是拆散它
We're trying to save our marriage, not destroy it.
-我不想分居  -讓她說完
- I don't want to do that. - Let her finish.
不用把這想像成分居
Don't think of it as a separation.
你們共同經歷了很多
You two have gone through so much.
跟你們剛在一起時相比
You're completely different people
你們現在是完全不同的人了
than when you first got together.
冷靜一下能幫你們重新找回自我
It can be helpful to rediscover who you are.
何不互相冷靜一段時間呢
Take a break from one another.
冷靜  分居  都是一回事
Break, separation -- it's the same thing.
都是離婚的第一步
It's the first step to divorce.
-你想冷靜嗎  你想嗎  -讓她說完
- Is this what you want? Is this what you -- - Let her finish.
以我的經驗來看  夫婦來接受心理指導
Look, in my experience, couples come to therapy
有兩個原因
for one of two reasons.
一個是一方想解除婚姻關係
Either one person wants out of the relationship
想找辦法告訴另一方
and they need help telling the other,
還有一個是他們都迫切地想重歸於好
or they both desperately want to make it work.
他們想努力輓救
They want to fight to make it work.
我們想和好  對不對
Well, we want to make it work, right?
對  對
Right. Right.
並不只是冷靜而已
And a break is not an end.
冷靜只是幫助你們和好的一種方式
A break is a tool to help make it work,
按照約定的期限冷靜一段時間後
for an agreed-upon time,
再回來重新審視你們的婚姻
and then we come together, re-evaluate the relationship.
我不要  我不喜歡  我不
No. I don't like it. I don't -- no.
這太荒唐了  對不起  我真這麼覺得
I think it's crazy. I'm sorry, I do.
我們的目的是要變得更親密
I-I mean, we're supposed to be getting closer,
為什麼反而需要更多空間
So, what, we need more space?
不對  我們要花更多時間在一起
No, we need more time together,
而不是分開
not apart.
這才是解決問題的辦法  不是嗎
That's how you make things work, right?
我們不要冷靜  是吧
No break, right?
我們要冷靜一段時間
I think we should take a break.
實習醫生格蕾
—
第十一季  第五集  "無法復原"
"Bend and Break"
要冷靜多久時間
How long -- how long will the break last?
多久都可以  我們現在就決定吧
As long as you'd like. We decide that now.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用於任何商業盈利行為
好吧  那就  三十天
Okay. Um...30 days?
翻譯  想往D  芝小士  konata77
翻譯  阿囧  宅女之後  小shy
三十天  一個月
30 days? A month?
你想跟我冷靜一整個月
You need a break from me for a whole month?
校對  宅女之後  喵記   醫學顧問  Lucifer
亞利桑那  你有想說的話現在可以說了
Arizona, you want to say something, now is the time.
時間軸  糖不甩  阿丹  靈媒
後期  Sung   總監  喵了個咪
凱麗  我已經很含蓄了
Callie, I was trying to be nice.
我覺得三十天都可能不夠
I-I don't even think that that'd be enough.
我要是早知道你會同意
I mean, if I thought you'd go for it,
我可能會說三個月或者六個月
maybe three months, six months.
我的天  六個月
Oh -- oh, my god. Six months?
我只是實話實說
I'm trying to be honest.
我想輓回  但我唯一知道的辦法
I want to save us, but the only way that I know
就是誠實
how to do this is by being honest.
這簡直就是個笑話
This feels like a joke.
或者真人秀
Or a reality show.
"西雅圖女同主婦兼醫生的真實生活"
"Real lesbian housewives M.D. of Seattle."
行  就三十天  我們要怎麼做
Fine, 30 days. How does it work?
你們有一個孩子  所以為她著想
You have a child, so for her sake,
你們倆以家長的身份一起住
you two will live in the house as parents,
但生活要分開  住不同房間
but with separate lives, separate rooms.
界限分明很重要
Boundaries are vital.
為照顧孩子分配好各自的責任
Make a schedule for child-care responsibilities,
要嚴格執行
and stick to it.
不能說話
No talking,
除非緊急情況  不能交流
no communication, except in emergencies.
最後這條很重要
Lastly -- this is important...
不能有親密舉動  不能上床
no intimacy, no sex,
不論是跟別人還是和彼此都不可以
with other people or with each other.
第1天
索菲亞穿好衣服了
Sofia's getting dressed.
這周她都一直喜歡
She also seems to be continuing
紫色調  停不下來
the purple theme she's got going on this week.
亞利桑那  我整晚都沒睡
Arizona, I didn't sleep at all.
我做不到
I can't do this.
已經一個晚上了
It's been one night, and, um...
我覺得我們不用這樣
I feel we don't need this.
我們怎麼可能一整個月不說話
How are we seriously supposed to not talk for an entire month?
求你看看我  我想說說話
Just -- please, just please look at me. I need to talk.
艾米莉  對不起  我知道很疼
Emily, I'm sorry. I know it hurts.
-痛死了  -藥很快就會起效了
-Hurts like a bitch. Yeah, meds will kick in soon.
你手臂被什麼卷進去來著
You got your arm caught in what, again?
做麵條的機器
A noodle-making machine.
這工作沒勁透了  不過工資不錯
It's the dumbest job ever, but it just pays well,
我想去烹飪學校學習
and I'm trying to get into culinary school,
學費能貴死人
which is freaking expensive.
看起來有粉碎性骨折  移位
Looks like comminuted, displaced,
-橈骨中端及尺骨骨折  -好的
- mid-shaft radius and ulna fractures. - Yep.
艾米莉
Well, Emily,
很不幸  你的手臂必須手術
unfortunately, your arm definitely needs surgery.
現在  要固定骨折部位
Now, in order to stabilize the fracture,
應該要用到金屬板和螺絲
I will most likely need to put in a plate and some screws.
愛德華茲  通知手術室
Uh, Edwards, call up to the O.R.
傷口要多久才能愈合
How long will it take to heal?
手臂康復我才能做菜  才能上學培訓
I need my arm in shape to cook, to train for school.
一個月後申請就截止了
Applications are due in a month.
你傷得很重
Well, obviously, it's a pretty bad fracture,
我們會把你治好的
but we will fix you up.
我們會儘快讓你進行理療
We will get you into P.T. as soon as we can,
你很快就能恢復了  知道嗎
and you will be back at it before you know it, okay?
好的
All right.
李·富蘭克林  剛出生一天
Lee Franklin, one day old,
患有先天性食管閉鎖
diagnosed with esophageal atresia at birth.
也就是說  他的食道
Which means that his esophagus
是兩截分開長的
developed in two separate pieces.
不好意思  你不是說能修補好空隙啊
I'm sorry, but I thought you said you could fix the gap.
要什麼時候補好
When is that gonna happen?
有個壞消息  李的片子顯示
Well, unfortunately, Lee's images show
空隙比我們預計的大
a longer gap than we predicted.
長度約有四釐米  所以我們不能
It's measuring around four centimeters, which prevents us
直接把兩端縫合
from simply sewing the two ends back together.
克萊夫醫生還是可以手術的
Dr. Karev can still operate.
只不過手術會更複雜些
It just makes the surgery a little bit more complicated.
威爾遜
Wilson?
我們會在李的兩截食道末端連上縫線
We'll attach sutures to both ends of Lee's esophagus,
穿過背部切口
threading them out through incisions in his back.
我們會每天扯縫線
Every day, we'll pull on the sutures,
讓裡面的食道末端伸長
thereby stretching the ends inside toward each other
在二次手術中連接兩端
in order to connect them in a later surgery.
但是  為了手術能順利進行
However, for the procedure to work,
李必須保持一動不動的姿勢
we'll need Lee to remain extremely still,
我們要讓他進入醫學誘導昏迷狀態
so we'll need to put him in a medically induced coma.
不好意思  羅賓斯醫生
I-I'm sorry, but, Dr. Robbins,
為什麼手術不是你做
but w-why aren't you doing the surgery?
你們的病例現在歸克萊夫醫生管
Dr. Karev is now the attending on this case.
最近我開始在另一個部門
I have recently started a new specialty
一個新的專業工作
in a different department.
但我向你們保證
But I can assure you,
克萊夫醫生是我教出來的  技術非常精湛
I trained Dr. Karev, and he is awesome.
你要讓我們寶寶陷入昏迷
Y-you have to put our baby into a coma?
要多久
For how long?
整個過程可能要好幾周
This process could take... weeks.
還有別的手術方式
There are other surgical options I'd love to go over --
但這種對李來說是最好的
But this is the best one for Lee.
羅賓斯醫生  能不能出來一下
Dr. Robbins, can I see you outside?
你怎麼回事
What was that?
你那樣說  他們會擔心的
You're just gonna make them worry.
我想做結腸間置術
I was thinking of doing a colonic interposition.
只要做一次手術  他就能回家了
I fix the kid in one surgery, he can go home sooner.
不行  用自然的食管最好
No, using the native esophagus is better.
雖然要住院很久  但是
It's a prolonged hospital stay, but --
我們要讓他昏迷好幾周  甚至好幾個月
We could have him in a coma for weeks, maybe months.
爸媽會擔心瘋了的
I mean, that'll put the parents through hell.
用結腸的話  食道狹窄  吻合處滲漏
Using the colon has increased risks of stricture,
和胃食道逆流性疾病的風險都會增加
anastomotic leaks, GRED.
眼睜睜看著孩子受這些苦當然也很折磨
I mean, it's not fun to watch your kid go through that, either.
你是要讓我自己完成工作
Are you gonna let me do my job,
還是要一直替我完成
or are you gonna do it for me the whole time?
糟糕  我巡房遲到了
Oh, crap, I'm late for rounds.
聽我說  按我說的做  好嗎
Okay, listen, just do it my way, okay?
行  就因為他曾經是你的病人
Fine, only because he was once your patient
你老是放不下
and because you're having trouble cutting the strings.
或者是因為你知道我是對的
Yeah, or because you know that I'm right.
這個給你  醫生
Here you go, doctor.
謝謝
Thanks.
我讓你丈夫到樓下的禮品商店去了
I sent your husband down to the gift shop.
我們上次聊到針的時候他直接昏倒了
He fainted last time we talked about needles.
他真的不能被嚇到
Oh, he's such a lightweight.
但願他會給你買巧克力
Well, hopefully, he's buying you some chocolate.
你遲到了
You're late.
對不起  我在看重症監護室的一個寶寶
I'm so sorry. Uh, I was checking on a baby in the NICU --
跟我無關  格雷漢姆  開始吧
Don't care. Graham, start talking.
傑奎琳·華連  懷孕23周
Jaclyn Werlein, 23 weeks along.
心臟超聲確診
Recent fetal echo of her baby's heart
胎兒患有嚴重主動脈瓣狹窄
unfortunately confirmed critical aortic stenosis.
為了打開胎兒狹窄的主動脈瓣
Today, we'll be performing a fetal aortic valvuloplasty
我們今天要進行主動脈瓣膜成形術
in order to open up the narrowed aortic valve.
你血壓有些高  沒事吧
Your B.P is a little high. You feeling okay?
我有點緊張
I'm a little nervous.
一想到有一根針要穿過我
The idea of a giant needle going through me
然後穿過我寶寶的小心臟
and then my baby's teeny heart...
這看上去是不允許有任何差錯的
There doesn't seem to be much room for error.
赫爾曼醫生讓這家醫院成為了
Dr. Herman has made us the go-to hospital
胎兒心臟介入治療的品牌醫院
for fetal cardiac intervention.
她是太平洋西北岸唯一會做這種手術的外科醫生
She is the only surgeon who even does this procedure in the Pacific northwest.
她是我來這兒的理由  向她學習
She's why I'm here... to learn from her.
傑奎琳  在我沒確定胎位正確之前
Jaclyn, I'm not even going to insert the needle
我是不會輕易插針的
until I'm sure your baby's in the precise position that he needs to be.
好的
Okay.
胎位是成功的關鍵
Position is critical to success.
假如胎兒沒有臉朝前  胸腔向上
If the fetus isn't facing forward, chest up,
我們無法達到心尖
we can't get to the apex of the heart.
做得好  格雷漢姆
Perfect approach, Graham.
我們現在有直接路徑了
We have direct access now.
我一直在實驗室裡反復練習
I've been practicing in the lab.
赫爾曼醫生  我很樂意幫忙
Dr. Herman, I'd be happy to assist.
這次由格雷漢姆協助  看好 記好
Graham is assisting on this one. Watch. Take notes.
我為嬰兒做過幾十次的穿刺手術
I've performed dozens of percutaneous procedures on babies.
這些嬰兒難道都還在子宮裡嗎
Were the babies still in utero?
他們的心臟都跟核桃一樣小嗎
Did they have hearts the size of a walnut?
不  沒有  但是
No. No, but...
那就是不一樣的  對嗎
Well, that's not the same, then, is it?
羅賓斯  你是一名出色的小兒外科醫生
Robbins, you have an impeccable record as a pediatric surgeon.
但是作為胎兒外科醫生  你得從零開始
As a fetal surgeon, big, fat zero.
我建議你仔細觀察格雷漢姆的手法
I suggest you pay close attention to Graham's hands,
下一次  你就是助手了
and next time, you can assist.
赫爾曼醫生  我只是在模仿你的手法而已
Well, Dr. Herman, my hands are only trying to emulate yours.
格雷漢姆  再多說一句  我就把你送到整形科
Graham, one more word, we're gonna go over to plastics
把你嘴縫起來  好讓你不要再拍馬屁
and have your lips surgically removed from my ass.
所有人都閉嘴  我在置入氣囊
Now, shut up, everyone. I'm deploying the balloon.
如果你感興趣的話
Oh, in case you're interested,
技能實驗室有一個模型可以供你練習
there's a model you can practice on in the skills lab.
很舊了  橡膠都硬了
It's old, and the rubber's hardened,
聞起來很噁心  祝你練得開心
and it smells gross, but have fun.
-謝謝  -我花了兩個月才練成的
- Thanks. - It took me about two months to nail it.
祝你好運
Good luck.
愛德華茲
Oh, Edwards, hey.
你今天還跟凱麗嗎
Um, are you still on Callie's service?
不行  這已經是她第四次叫我替她照顧索菲亞了
No, this is the fourth time that she has switched Sofia duty on me.
她說她得練習
She said she had to practice.
你告訴她  她女兒問她
You tell her that her daughter's asking
什麼時候才有時間哄她入睡
when she's gonna tuck her in at night,
並且提醒她這樣愚蠢的安排下
and remind her that we share custody
-我們是共同承擔撫養權的  -這事不太適合
- in this stupid arrangement. - Okay, this really isn't something
-讓我去  -出去  愛德華茲
- that I feel comfortable - Get out, Edwards.
不好意思
Oh, sorry.
你剛剛在說  甲狀腺癌
You were saying, uh, thyroid cancer?
病人叫大衛·拉舍
Patient is David Lasher.
我給他做過甲狀腺切除術
I did a thyroidectomy on him,
從那時開始  他的癌症好了
and since then, he has been cancer-free,
但今早他來醫院說髖部疼痛
but this morning, he came in complaining of hip pain,
所以我做了一個正子斷層掃瞄
So I did a pet scan, and...
骨頭病灶轉移到髖部了
Bone mets to the hip.
有沒有辦法切除腫瘤
Is there any way to resect this
但不需要髖關節置換手術
without doing a total hip replacement?
不行  看上去牽扯了很多股骨近端
No, it looks like it involves too much of the proximal femur.
-大衛幾歲了  -33歲  有妻子和兩個孩子
- How old is David? - 33, two kids and a wife.
如果置換的話  能維持多長時間
How long will a replacement last?
十到十五年吧
Uh, 10, 15 years.
所以他肯定需要再接受一次置換手術
So he'll need another one eventually.
沒錯  但是我們要麼切除和置換髖關節
Well, yeah, but we either resect it and do a total hip now,
要麼他的癌症持續擴散  他會死的
or his cancer continues to spread, and he dies.
好吧  看上去我要安排一個髖關節置換手術了
Well, it looks like I'm scheduling a hip replacement.
哦  不
Yeah. Oh, no.
不要現在安排  我得...
Don't -- don't schedule it now. I have a..
去接孩子
a kid to pick up.
而且你得面帶笑容
And you have to keep on a smile on your face
即使你的另一半幾乎不和你說話
despite your spouse barely speaking to you.
我十分理解
Totally get that.
晚安
Good night.
好夢
Sweet dreams.
去了很多地方才找到這個  但總算找到了
I had to look at so many places to find this, but I did.
凱麗
Hey, Callie.
我們是不是會吵到索菲亞
Are we too loud for Sofia?
不會  我剛剛哄她睡下  我以為
No, I just put her down. I thought y...
我以為亞利桑那要學習
I thought Arizona had to study.
對  你們倆講話是違規
Right, uh, talking is against the rules.
對不起  亞利桑那是在學習
Sorry. Yes, Arizona is studying.
我在幫她製作可以練習使用的果凍母體
I am helping her make jello moms to practice on.
果凍就是子宮
The jello is the uterus,
葡萄就是嬰兒的小心臟
and the grapes -- tiny, little baby hearts.
簡直是最完美的手術模型
It's the perfect surgical model.
-可以從這  -真棒
- You go in right here, and... - Neat.
我還在製作鮮果色拉
I'm also making ambrosia salad --
凱普娜家族秘方
Kepner family recipe.
然後你做了什麼
So, then what did you do?
我遵守了規則
I followed the rules.
順便說一句  你的規則爛透了
Your rules, by the way...they suck.
第10天
好的  馬上就好了
Okay, almost there.
胎兒左肩再往下一點  往下
Just move the baby's left shoulder down, down.
很好  恭喜你  羅賓斯
Okay. That's good. Congratulations, Robbins.
你是我見過的最快
That was the fastest I've ever seen anyone
將胎位移正的人
flip a fetus into position.
謝謝誇獎  赫爾曼醫生
Thank you, Dr. Herman.
一旦針插進去
So, once we get the needle in,
你想完成接下來的手術嗎
you want to do the rest of the procedure?
當然想
Yes.
但是我不  不確定我是否可以
But I'm not... I'm not sure I should.
我只在技能實驗室裡練習過幾次
I've only practiced a couple times in the skills lab,
我不知道我是否已經夠格
and I-I don't know if I'm there yet.
如果她沒準備好  我很樂意幫忙
Well, I'm happy to assist if she's not ready.
格雷漢姆  我要你特別注意羅賓斯剛才的手法
Graham, I want you to take special note of what Robbins did there.
哦  是的
Oh, yes, ma'am.
我看到了
I-I-I saw it.
有經驗的醫生能夠
That's what being an experienced surgeon gains you...
讓你了解自己的侷限
the wisdom to know your limitations.
她不會讓她的自滿
She's not gonna let her own arrogance
妨礙到病人的健康
get in the way of patient care.
做得好  羅賓斯
Good call, Robbins.
大家做的都很好
Nice work, guys.
羅賓斯  下一次你做主刀  準備好
Robbins, you'll take the lead on the next one. Be ready.
沒問題  赫爾曼醫生
Of course, Dr. Herman.
太好了
Yes!
艾米麗  請不要動
Oh, Emily, I need you to remain still.
我以為做了手術我就不會疼了
I thought the surgery was supposed to fix it!
還是很痛  比剛出事的時候還要痛
It still hurts, almost worse than when it got caught!
你手術才剛過一周  艾米麗
Okay, well, you're a little over a week post-op, Emily.
有時還是會疼的  愛德華茲  讀數
It's still gonna hurt from time to time. Edwards, labs?
血液運行完全正常
Her blood work's completely normal.
切口看起來正常
Uh, the incision looks good...
沒有感染跡象  沒有間隔綜合徵
No sign of infection, no compartment syndrome.
我簡直寢食難安
I can't sleep. I can't eat. Oh!
每分鐘都要感受像這樣的陣痛兩三次
I get these shocks like two or three times a minute,
我堅持不下去了  托瑞斯醫生
and I -- I can't do it, Dr. Torres.
艾米麗  抱歉  所有檢查都做過了
Emily, I am so sorry. I-I've run every test.
沒有任何異常
Nothing's coming up.
-我不知道該怎麼辦  -想想辦法
- I'm not sure what I can do. - Something!
你們得想辦法幫幫我
You got to do something to help me.
這樣我活不下去
I can't live like this.
早知道會像這樣
If I had known it was gonna be like this...
求你了
Please.
抱歉
Sorry.
你沒事吧
You're good? You okay?
我還好嗎
Am I good?
我很顯然不好  很顯然有事
I am obviously not good. I'm obviously not okay.
你為什麼要明知故問呢
Why would you ask that if you already know the answer?
怎麼不問  "凱麗發生什麼事了"
Why not try, "What is it, Callie?"
像個正常人一樣問我  "我能幫你什麼  凱麗"
"What can I do, Callie," like a human person?
抱歉  我自己也有煩心事
Sorry. I have my own stuff.
不  我...
No, I'm s..
對不起  是我的錯
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
我  我只是找不到人傾訴
I just...I have no one to talk to.
-你現在值班嗎  -不  怎麼了
- You on call right now? - No, why?
-再來兩杯  -好的
- Two more.  - Alright.
現在是同住一家不睡一床啊
It's called an in-home separation.
我們住在一個屋檐下
We live in the same house.
輪流照顧索非亞
We trade off caring for Sofia.
但就是不交流也不滾床單
We just can't talk or have sex.
我跟德裡克也這樣  清心寡慾健康康
Exactly what Derek and I are doing, only healthy.
說得好  乾杯
Oh. Well, cheers to that.
所謂的"堅強不倒翁"
Good man in the storm.
此處指亞利桑那,詳情請看第六季第五集,亞利桑那對凱麗父親說自己名字的由來,"I was raised to be a good man in a storm."
再堅強不也得分居麼
What's so "Good man in the storm" about a break?
"你今天過得怎樣  梅瑞狄斯"
"How was your day, Meredith?
"你今天有救活病人嗎  梅瑞狄斯
"Did you cure death today, Meredith?
你打算什麼時候救到病人  梅瑞狄斯
When are you gonna cure death, Meredith?"
-男人真磨嘰  -"如果你讓我去華盛頓
- Oh, god. - “I could have cured death
為總統工作  我能救到很多人"
if you let me move to D.C. and work for the president."
老娘就是雙性戀  怎麼著
So I'm bisexual! So what?
這是既定的事實
It's a thing, and it's real.
LGBTQ可不是白起的
I mean it's called LGBTQ for a reason.
LGBTQ:女同性戀 男同性戀 雙性戀 跨性別戀 疑性戀
裡面可涵蓋了雙
There's a "B" in there,
雙又不是渣
and it doesn't mean "Badass."
雖然會有些渣渣  但我不是
Okay, it kind of does, but it also means Bi.
我媽跟主任"爽"遍了整個醫院
My mom and the chief were doing it all over the hospital.
醫院裡無處不是"戰場"
All over the hospital,
就像我和德裡克那時  背著艾蒂遜偷歡
like me and Derek -- cheating on Addison.
我完美繼承了"劈腿基因"
I'm a legacy cheater.
也許索非亞也會繼承"劈腿基因"
Maybe Sofia will be a legacy cheater.
這醫院的所有人都耍過我
Everyone in this hospital's cheated on me.
我每一個結婚對象都出軌了
Every single person I have ever married has cheated on me --
好吧  也就兩個
All, uh, two of them?
對
Yeah.
加油乾了它
Come on.
克里斯蒂娜是我的第三者
Cristina was the third rail in our marriage --
危險  充滿激情  足以拆散我們夫妻
Dangerous, fully charged, could kill us,
但我無法和她斷交
But necessary for us to keep going.
她確實太懂我
She got me.
你覺得
You think it's possible
我一生中的摯愛有可能是個女的嗎
that my one true love in my life is a girl?
你看到她的"妹妹"性奮了嗎
Did you get excited by her vagina?
沒有
No.
那就不是
Then no.
說得對
Good point.
*百合*
*Vagina*
*小百合*  *小百合*
*Va-va-vagina*   *Vagina*
唱出來
Sing it.
*百呀嘛小百合*
*Va-va-vagina*
-*百合喲羅嘿* -這真是個好奇葩的詞
- *Vagi-na-ha* - It's a weird word.
我覺得唱著挺好聽的
I think it sounds pretty.
人們不該忌諱說這詞
People should say it more.
天  老娘太久沒爽了
Oh, god, I miss sex.
老娘這麼性感  我老公卻是個白痴
I'm hot. My husband's an idiot.
乾了它
Do it.
等會估計要吐了
That might come back up.
你們破戒了
So, you broke the rules.
不不不  我們及時停手了
No. No, we stopped.
我們沒上床
We didn't have sex.
我們只是  開始接吻
We j-- we just -- we kissed and,
然後不知怎麼就停下了
uh, somehow stopped.
她那天和赫爾曼醫生做了台大手術
I mean, she'd had that big surgery with Dr. Herman that day,
我只是想跟她了解情況
and all I wanted to do was ask her how it went.
我們沒上床
We didn't have sex.
但差點上了
Close enough.
我倒希望真做了呢
Well, now I wish that we had't stopped. So, uh...
那現在怎麼辦
So, what happens now?
你們真想最後成功的話
In order for this to work,
就得繼續30天不接觸彼此
you have to follow the rules for the full 30 days.
你不是說真的吧
You don't mean...
你打算什麼時候做吻合手術
When are you planning on doing the anastomosis?
一到兩天內  只要近得可以連起來就做
Ends will be close enough to join in a day or two.
最新一次食管間隙分析顯示快接近了
Latest gapogram shows we're almost there.
你每天牽拉多長
How much are you pulling each day?
大概兩毫米
Uh, about two millimeters.
一毫米更安全點
Oh. One's safer.
你來這幹嘛
Why are you up here again?
你聽清楚我做了什麼麼
Do you even know what I'm doing?
我把一根只有頭髮絲粗的金屬線
I am taking a wire the width of a hair
穿過一個母親的腹部
and maneuvering it through the mom's abdomen,
進入子宮
into the uterus,
然後穿過羊膜腔
and then through the amniotic cavity,
進入小胎兒的胸部
and then into the tiny fetus' chest,
直達異常小的心臟  拯救了這個小生命
into an insanely tiny heart, to save a tiny human.
是  是  你真棒
Hm. Yay, you.
嘿  溫柔點
Ok-- y-- hey, pull gently.
我很溫柔了  閉嘴好嗎
I am. Stop it.
就因為我做的這些  你都不用再給她做什麼手術了
Think about all the surgeries I'll save you from having to do.
記得提醒我過會答謝你
Remind me to thank you later.
現在可以請你離開了嗎
Now, would you please --
我的工作完爆你的了咧
My job's gonna make your job obsolete.
-糟糕  -阿歷克斯  你怎麼
- Damn it. - Oh, Alex, no!
你是說還得再做一次手術
You're saying we have to start this whole ordeal over again?
我們得在手術室重新連接李的縫合部位
Since we had to reattach Lee's sutures in the O.R.,
所以又得回到幾天前的情況
it did set us back a few days.
但我保證  這手術特別簡單
But I assure you, it's a minor complication of the technique.
別跟我說手術簡單
Nothing about this is minor!
要真簡單  你們還能讓他病情惡化了啊
Now it sounds like you've just made him worse!
親愛的  也許
Honey, maybe this
她一次也沒抱過自己的孩子
she hasn't held her son once.
你知道這是什麼感受麼
Do you know what that's like for her,
她呆立於此
For her to stand here
看著他全身插著管子  而無能為力
and just see him covered in tubes?
先生  我很抱歉
Sir, I'm very sorry.
你才是該抱歉的那個
You're the one who should be the one apologizing.
本該是你來做手術的
You were supposed to do the surgery,
但你卻交給他來做
but you just passed it off to him!
我向你保證克萊夫醫生
I assure you that Dr. Karev --
對  他很棒  手術一流  我們知道
Yeah, he's very good. He's "Awesome." We remember.
然後我兒子胸部又要開刀
My baby boy's chest has now been cut into twice,
所以我實在不覺得他有多好
so you'll forgive me if I don't share your opinion.
阿歷克斯  我很抱歉
Alex, hey, I'm s--
不  該道歉的是我
No, I'm sorry.
我早該跟你說實話
I'm sorry for not telling you this sooner.
我不該聽你的
I never should have let you
做這個我自己都覺得不對的手術
dictate a procedure I don't believe in.
這是我的病人
This is my patient,
就該聽我的
This is my service,
這是我的新生兒加護病房
this is my nicu.
而我還記得
And last time I checked,
我是主治醫生  你只是個進修醫生
I was the attending, and you were a fellow,
所以你別再越權  趕緊滾出我的樓層
So stop overstepping, and get the hell off my floor now!
第16天
損傷在擴大
This lesion is extending
一路穿過大衛的大轉子下區
all the way across David's subtroch region.
真不敢相信這麼久以來
I can't believe he made it this far
他整個股骨都沒斷
without fracturing his entire femur.
"分手"情況如何
How's the break going?
梅瑞狄斯
Meredith.
我是指和美食分手
I mean, diet.
-分得怎樣  -美食啊  對
- How's the diet going? - Diet, right.
我想應該都重回正軌了吧
Uh, I'm back on track, I think.
畢竟第16天了
Day 16.
沒有再晚上大吃大喝[縱欲過度]了吧
No more late-night binges?
我差點就    吃了芝士漢堡[暗指滾床單]
Well, I almost had a, uh, cheeseburger,
但後來沒吃了  所以
but then I didn't, so --
那真是折磨  因為我愛死芝士漢堡
That was rough, 'cause I like cheeseburgers.
天啊  我真懷念芝士漢堡
Oh, god, I miss cheeseburgers.
德裡克每晚都想吃芝士漢堡
Derek wants a cheeseburger every single night,
我告訴他沒過今年不能吃
and I tell him he can't have one till the end of the year,
所以他只能睡沙發了
so he should just go and sleep on the couch.
你真幸運
You're lucky.
至少你飲食計劃看得到頭  30天是吧
At least your diet has an end date -- 30 days, right?
想象一下飲食計劃結束後  能嘗到
Imagine how good that cheeseburger's gonna taste
-芝士漢堡的那種美味  -別再說了
- when your diet's done. - No.
說太過了麼
Did I go too far?
不不不  你看這
No, no, no. Look, look.
看到炎症灶了嗎
See that inflammation?
這裡完全失去血供了
The blood supply's completely gone.
全髂關節置換沒法做
A total hip won't survive in here.
差勁的治療  蹩腳的外科床
Poor healing, crappy surgical bed,
免疫功能低下
his immunocompromised state --
一周內很可能就會感染
it'd be infected within a week.
那你要怎麼辦
So, what do you want to do?
我們把腫瘤和壞死的骨頭一併摘除了
We removed the tumor along with the necrotic bone,
並清洗病灶處
and we completely washed out the area.
炎症非常嚴重
It was fairly inflamed,
所以我們放置了一個抗生素骨水泥占位器
so we also placed antibiotic-loaded cement spacers.
所以現在他沒有髂骨了
So, right now, he has no hip?
那他怎麼下床或走路
H-how can he get out of bed or walk?
沒辦法
He can't.
唯一將他的腿跟其餘身體連接著的
That ex-fix I attached is the only thing
是我前一次做的修補
securing his leg in place to the rest of his body.
天啊  為什麼你
Oh, god. Why did you...
你說過你很擅長這類手術
You said that you do this all the time.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
在沒查看過你丈夫腿內的情況前
I didn't know how much damage there would be
我們都不知道損傷這麼嚴重了
until we actually opened your husband up.
前一次修補只是權宜之計
The ex-fix is only temporary.
我們會找到長久之計
We will find a permanent solution.
關鍵是我們摘掉了腫瘤
The important thing is we got the tumor,
防止它再給大衛帶來更多麻煩
and we stopped it from causing David any more problems.
我要  我要陪著他
I need -- I need to be with him.
當然
Of course.
天啊  我這個月糟糕透了
Oh, god, I'm having the worst month.
我知道我們需要什麼了
I know what we need.
你太機智了  太機智了
Oh, you are so smart -- so smart.
-這麼多吃不完啊  -沒關係
- Can't eat all of this. - Oh, no, no.
我們分著吃
We'll split it.
乾杯
Cheers.
-等等  -怎麼了
- Wait. - What?
-我們可以分開  -沒錯啊
- We could split it. - We are.
不是這個意思  不如我們把它分開
No, no, no. What if we -- what if we split it?
如果你想吃一整個  你就吃吧
If you want the whole thing, you can have the whole thing.
不  說的是大衛的腿  這想法太妙了
No, the leg, the -- for David, the -- look, it's genius.
如果我們把腓骨分成兩半
If we take his fibula bone and we split it into two pieces,
我們就可以用它填補腫瘤切除後的空隙
we can use that to bridge the gap from the tumor resection.
腓骨上仍保留了原本的血管
The fibula will still have its native vessel
可以用作架接
that we can attach.
所以是把肉莖搭上旋動脈上
So, you attach the pedicle to the circumflex artery
再把壞死骨掏空
and then core out the necrotic bone?
-能這樣做嗎  -這是治療骨不合的做法
- You do that? - Works for non-unions.
用於腫瘤切除術也肯定沒問題
I don't see why it wouldn't work for a tumor.
-他的腿還能救回來嗎  -是的
- And he still gets to keep his leg? - Yes!
好啦  我們再要點醃黃瓜
Okay, we're gonna need more pickles.
我們又破戒了
We broke the rules again.
-你們上床了 -沒  不是
- So, you had sex? - No, no.
她有天沒回家
When she didn't come home,
我以為她跟別人睡了
I thought she was sleeping with someone else,
這就是破戒
which is against the rules,
我一直糾結這個想法
And, also, the idea really, really bugged me.
然後我又想  要是她沒有這樣做
And then, when I thought, well, if she's not doing that,
如果她出事了怎麼辦
then what if she's not okay?
這就讓我更糾結了
'cause that bugged me more.
所以我跟她說話了
So, I made her talk to me.
我知道我們不該講話
So, I know that we're not supposed to,
但我們住在同一屋檐下
but we still live in the same house,
所以我知道你沒回家
so I know when you don't come home.
是的
Okay.
我知道這不關我事  但我們還有索菲亞
And I know it's none of my business, but there's Sofia,
所以如果你發生什麼事了
And so, you know, if something were to happen to you,
我都不知道你在哪  和誰在一起
I wouldn't know where you were or who you were with.
-我在醫院  -別騙我
- I was here. - Don't.
好嗎  我查了你的問診記錄
Okay? 'cause I searched the call records for your name.
-所以你監視我  -我很擔心
- Oh, so you stalked me? - I was worried.
我和格蕾一起吃晚飯
I was at dinner with Grey.
我們想到治療病人的方法
We came up with a fix for a patient,
所以我們返回醫院繼續工作
and we came back here to work on it.
-和梅瑞狄斯嗎  -是的  怎麼了
- With Meredith? - Yes. What?
什麼  你以為有什麼
What, you think something ha--
我和梅瑞狄斯·格蕾一起工作到凌晨三點
I was with Meredith Grey, and suddenly, it was 3:00 a.M.
我不想開車回家  所以在待命室睡著了
I didn't want to drive home, so I slept in an on-call room.
她吃醋了
She was jealous --
很不理智  明顯吃醋了
Like, irrationally, obviously jealous.
你知道這感覺嗎  有人為你吃醋
Do you know how that feels, to have someone be jealous,
擔心你出軌
to be worried that you're cheating?
這感覺不錯
It feels nice.
這種想法不是很健康
Well, it's not the healthiest --
不  不  不  我意思是
No, no, no, no, no, I just mean,
她擔心我
she was -- she was worried about me.
她在意我
She -- she cared.
是不是意味著我們分開一段時間是對的
Does that mean this thing might actually be working?
等我幾分鐘
All right, just give me a few minutes,
我會給你送去
and I will have viable
結構完整的好骨頭
and structurally sound bone coming your way.
沒有在轉子下區發現任何感染
There's no sign of infection in the subtroch region,
抗生素隔離有效果
so the antibiotic spacers worked.
-血液供應如何  -非常好
- How's the blood supply? - Oh, it's freaking amazing.
我們會使用
All right, we'll use a portion
腓骨動脈和周圍的靜脈
of the peroneal artery and its adjoining veins.
好了  我等你處理完
Okay, ready when you are.
當我處理完股管
All right, after I finish the femoral canal,
我們就會把
we will incorporate the fibula
腓骨和板釘結構結合在一起修復缺陷
into a plate-and-screw construct to span the defect.
然後用8號尼龍線做血管接合
And we'll do the vessel anastomosis with an 8-0 nylon,
之後採用簡單的間接縫合
and we'll do simple, interrupted sutures.
接下來檢查滲漏
Then we will check for leaks
然後用脂肪移植修復滲漏
and patch any we find with fat grafts.
希望在幾周內
Hopefully, we'll have
我們可以讓病人承重
the patient weight-bearing within a couple of weeks.
-有其他問題嗎  -托瑞斯醫生
- Any Questions? - Dr.Torres.
-在  -手術結束後
- Yes? - When you're done in here,
-他們讓你去下急診室  -為什麼
- they're asking that you go down to the E.R. - Why?
推注50單位芬太尼
Push 50 of fentanyl.
發生什麼事了
What happened?
護理人員說
Paramedics said she ran her car
她開車衝出護欄撞到樹上了
straight through a guard rail and into a tree.
幸好沒有喪命
She's lucky to be alive.
停下來
Make it stop.
讓我死吧  請停下來
Let me die. Please, make it stop.
她是故意這麼做的嗎
Did she do it on purpose?
她現在神志不清
We can't get anything out of her right now that makes sense.
天啊
Oh, god.
等等  凱麗
Wait, Callie.
你和這女孩怎麼回事
What's the story with this girl?
一個月前我修復了她的手臂骨折
I repaired her arm fracture a month ago,
但她一直疼痛難耐
but she's still in horrible pain,
我也找不出原因
and I-I can't find anything wrong with her.
她沒有任何問題
There's nothing wrong with her.
我不知道是牽涉性疼痛
I don't know if it's referred pain
-或是奇怪的幻肢痛  -聽著
- or some kind of weird phantom limb, but... - Okay, listen.
我覺得她是想自殺
...I think she just tried to kill herself.
別說不是我的錯  因為這就是我的錯
And don't tell me it's not my fault, because it is.
這是我的錯
It's my fault.
我沒能停止她的疼痛
It's my fault that I can't stop the pain.
不要說了
Stop.
那  看到了嗎
There, see? You see that?
那些小東西嗎  很難看清楚啊
Those teeny things? Barely.
這些是積液囊腫
They're fluid-filled cysts.
艾米麗手臂的傷拉斷了脊髓的神經
Emily's arm injury ripped the nerves from her spinal cord,
導致了脊髓癲癇
causing her to develop spinal epilepsy.
但她沒有癲癇的癥狀  她的癥狀是
Instead of having seizures, she develops these --
陣痛
Shocks of pain.
-有辦法  -治療嗎  有  不過很危險
- Is there any way to -- - Fix it? Yeah. It's risky.
我要燒掉脊椎的神經末梢
I have to burn the nerve endings of her spine
來停止疼痛信號傳遞到手臂
to stop the communication of the pain signals to her arm.
你能做嗎
Oh. Can you do it?
有我不能的麼
Are you kidding me?
所以  艾蒂遜·蒙特瑪麗帶著孩子
So... Addison Montgomery with a toddler.
沒錯
Oh, yeah.
亨利徹底毀了她的白墻和白地毯
Henry has completely destroyed her white walls and carpets.
他現在喜歡畫畫
He's currently into drawing
亂灑東西  亂涂亂畫
and spilling and smearing.
是啊  看來我們有一段時間
Yeah, well, looks like we won't see her
不會在會議上見到她了
on the conference circuit for a little while.
我不知道你也認識艾蒂遜啊
Um, I didn't know that you knew Addison, too.
你查完房了嗎
Did you finish rounding?
是的
Yes.
是的  我來跟你說
Y-yeah. I w-wanted to tell you
錢女士簽了瓣膜成形術的同意書
that Ms.Cain gave consent to her valvuloplasty.
-要安排手術嗎  -好  安排在後天
- Um, should I schedule it? - Yeah. Day after next.
你來做主刀醫生  羅賓斯
And you're leading this one, Robbins.
格雷漢姆會負責協助和拿針
Graham will assist and hold the needles.
我旁觀
I'll observe.
這次你該準備好了吧
You be ready this time.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
還有其他事嗎
Did you need something else?
沒有
N-no.
-亨利啊  名字很可愛啊  -是啊
- So, Henry -- that's a cute name, though. - It’s cute.
他怎樣了
Hey, um, how's he doing?
我能看看他最近的食管間隙分析嗎
Can I see the most recent gapogram?
我不能給你看
Uh, I'm not sure that I should.
我就走
I'm leaving, okay?
這是你的病人  你管理新生兒監護病房
It's your -- your patient, your NICU,
你的地盤  我走就是了
your territory, so I'm gone.
看到脊髓了
Okay, cord's exposed.
我將插入無線電頻率探測儀
I'm about to send down the radio-frequency probe.
我只注意到手臂的傷
I never even thought to look past the arm, and now
我很可能毀了她去上廚藝學習的機會
I may have blown her chances at culinary school --
讓她離不開止痛藥了
Gotten her hooked on pain meds, to boot.
不是你的錯
It's not your fault.
這個問題
No, this -- this problem goes much deeper
不是之前你能看見或控制的
than anything you could have seen or could have controlled.
完全不是你的錯
It's not your fault at all.
卡莉歐碧  我
Calliope. I --
-我得練習  -別說話
- I need to practice. - No talking.
明天就是最後一天了
Tomorrow's the last day.
不做最後一步就成了
So? Close enough, right?
如果她要我們重頭再來怎麼辦
Oh, what if she makes us start over again?
那我們不告訴她就好了
So, what if we don't tell her?
我剛剛收到你的傳呼
Hey, um, I just got your page.
我以為錢的瓣膜成型
I thought the Cain valvuloplasty
是定在明天的
was scheduled for tomorrow.
原來是的
It was.
超聲顯示胎兒輕度水腫
Ultrasound showed mild fetal hydrops.
所以這手術不僅是要在今天做
So not only does it have to happen today...
而且是馬上就做
it has to happen right now.
你準備好了嗎
You ready?
準備好了
Ready.
穿刺針
Needle, please?
停
Stop.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
這我該問你
I should be asking you that.
對不起  我不明白
I'm sorry. I don't follow.
你猶豫了
You hesitated.
你試著扶穩你的手  我看見了
You steadied your hand. I watched you.
沒有  沒有  我很好
No, no, I'm fine.
-你緊張嗎  -不
- Are you nervous? - No.
我是說  我當然緊張  但是
I mean -- of course I am, but --
為什麼  為什麼緊張  你沒睡好嗎
Why? Why are you nervous? Are you well-rested?
睡得很好  赫爾曼醫生
Yes, Dr. Herman.
你認真準備了  是嗎
But you're prepared, right?
你研究胎兒超聲了嗎
You studied the fetal echo,
記住了測量結果了嗎
you memorized the measurements,
練習進針角度了嗎
you practiced the angles?
你知道穿刺針要穿多少進去嗎
Do you know exactly how far to insert the needle,
什麼時候該插入導絲  什麼時候給氣囊充氣
at which point to deploy the wire, inflate the balloon?
我知道  我覺得
I do. I think I --
你覺得  還是你知道
Do you think, or you know?
我知道  我知道
I know. I know. I know!
格雷漢姆  和羅賓斯換下位置
Graham, trade places with Robbins.
太好了
Absolutely.
-赫爾曼醫生  我  -好了
- Dr. Herman, I -- - It's fine.
不要再浪費寶貴的時間了
We've just lost some valuable time.
-你去哪了  -度假
- Where you been? - Vacation.
就到這裡吧
Right in here is fine.
請允許我解釋
Let me just explain.
你知道密西西比河以西[美國過半國土面積]
Do you know how many fetal surgeons there are
有多少胎兒外科醫生嗎
west of the Mississippi River?
五個  只有五個
Five. There are five of us.
我想要第六個  羅賓斯  所以我選了你
And I need a sixth, Robbins, so I picked you.
所有人中  我慎重地選擇了你
Out of everyone, I handpicked you.
而你現在讓我非常失望
And you are letting me down.
我不只質疑你的能力了
I'm not just questioning your abilities.
我都質疑我的能力了
Now I'm questioning mine.
我以為你有天賦
I thought you had something.
我以為你與眾不同
I thought you were special.
你是兒外科主任
You're the chief of pediatric surgery.
你是董事會成員
You're a member of the board,
在同事中有口皆碑
well-respected among peers.
我以為你能更快更好地進步
I thought you would be better and in less time.
但今天  今天你讓我難堪
But today? Today, you embarrassed me.
今天是你第二次毫無準備
Today, you were unprepared for the second time.
所以我可能得重新考慮
So I might have to rethink this,
因為你很可能並不具備我要的素質
because you might not have what it takes here.
我不知道你出了什麼問題
I don't know what's wrong with you.
我不知道你是不是中邪了
I don't know what kind of demons you have.
但我可以告訴你  你已落後學習進度了
But I can tell you that you are behind in this fellowship,
我可沒有時間讓你慢慢趕上來
and I don't have time for you to catch up.
我沒有時間允許你再次失敗
I don't have time for three strikes.
這種事情再有一次  你就被開除了
Something like this happens again, you're out.
-疼嗎  -不疼
- Any pain? - No.
完全不疼了
It's all gone.
你的胳膊呢
What about your arm?
沒有問題
Nothing.
當我的車撞到樹時
When my car hit that tree,
我腦子裡第一個念頭是
the first thought that came into my head was,
"至少可以結束了"  沒有疼痛
"At least it's over" -- no more pain,
不用再大把吃藥
no more swallowing a bunch of pills,
想盡辦法止痛
trying to make it stop,
不用再躲在沙發上哭
no more crying on my couch
看著那些愚蠢低端的烹飪節目
watching those stupid, cheesy cooking shows,
想著自己再也不能下廚了
thinking about food I'd never make.
上帝啊  我不用再為自己感到難過了
And, god, stop feeling sorry for myself.
謝謝你們
Thank you.
我終於感覺自己可以度過這次難關
I finally feel like I might actually survive this.
多虧了有你
That's all you, you know.
他還有很長的路要走  持久的功能鍛煉
Well, he's got a tough road ahead -- months of P.T. --
但那塊骨瓣應該可以支持他很多年
But that graft should last him for years.
希望這是他最後一次忍受痛苦
Hopefully, this is the beginning of the end for him.
你怎麼樣了
So, what about you?
第三十天了  是吧
It's day 30, isn't it?
是的
It is.
第三十天
Day 30.
很奇怪  我有點緊張了
Uh, I am...weirdly nervous.
我感覺很好  但我  我不知道
I mean, I feel good, but I -- I don't know.
就好像從外面回家了
It feels like coming back from somewhere.
雖然節食結束了
Well, even though the diet's over,
我仍然隨時可以奉陪吃漢堡喝龍舌蘭
I'm always up for cheeseburgers and tequila.
吃真的漢堡[不是上床]
Actual cheeseburgers.
當混亂平息
Once the chaos subsides,
我們得回到原點
we have to go back...
重新檢視
...take another look.
我們得捫心自問
We have to ask ourselves...
破碎的肢體能否再拼回來
...can this body be put back together?
我們把李的食管重新接了起來
We were able to put Lee's esophagus back together,
並且我可以保證  比之前的還要牢靠
and I assure you, it's stronger than ever.
非常感謝
Thank you so much.
如果我們處理正確  那就可以
If we've done our jobs right, it can.
止血
We stop the bleeding.
縫合創傷
We sew up the damage.
身體被我們拼湊完整
We make the body whole again.
我明白這麼做的意義了
I understand why we did this.
這讓我們更堅強  讓我們更美好
You know, it was to make us stronger, to make us better.
確實是這樣
And it did.
我感覺確實有作用
I mean, I feel like it really did.
花了不少時間
It took a long time,
過程很痛苦  讓人難過
and it was painful, and it sucked,
但  我們熬過來了
but...we've come a long way.
我知道我們還有更長的路要走  但是
And I know that we have further to go, but...
我愛你  卡莉歐碧
I love you, Calliope.
我愛你
I love you.
沒你的生活讓我恐懼
Life without you terrifies me.
那樣的世界沒有意義
And the world is just making less and less sense,
我不知道我工作時都在幹什麼
and, like, I don't know what I'm doing at work anymore,
而我需要一個依靠
but the thing that I need is my anchor.
那就是你
It's you.
我需要你
I need you.
你是我唯一需要的
And you're the only thing that I will ever need.
我很高興這一切都結束了
And I'm so glad that this break is over.
過去的三十天
The last 30 days
讓我學會很多
have taught me so much.
我們第一次來這時
And all I wanted when we first came here
我只想我們能繼續在一起
was to know that we would leave together.
但從我坐下來的那刻開始  我就感覺到
But from the minute I sat down, I could feel it.
我感覺到我快要窒息了
I felt like I was gonna be suffocated.
過去的幾周
The last several weeks,
我笑得更多  做了更多的事
I have laughed more, I have done more,
自己更加開心  而且
I have enjoyed myself more, than...
我終於體會到了自由
...and I finally feel free.
而一旦自由了
And by being free,
我就發現正是不斷努力輓回我們的關係
I can see now that constantly trying to fix us
讓我逐漸失去自我
is the thing that's been killing me slowly.
我不想再那樣了
And I don't want to do it anymore.
我不想再彌補什麼輓回我們
I don't want to fix it or fix us anymore.
也許除了如此努力地愛你  我應該
Maybe instead of loving you so hard, I should...
我應該暫時先做做自己
I should be myself for a while.
我應該愛我自己
I should love me,
你也應該愛你自己
and you should love you,
我們一起愛著索菲亞  而不是
and together we love Sofia, rather than...
我不能和你繼續走下去了  亞利桑那
I want so much for you, Arizona.
我們不能再繼續了
For both of us.
我們不能再像這樣糾結下去
So much more than this.
像這樣和同樣感到糾結的人糾結在一起
More than being stuck with someone who feels stuck.
我希望你也能感到自由
I want you to feel free, too.
但不管我們多麼努力地嘗試
But no matter how hard we try...
我們必須明白
...we have to realize...
有些事情
...some things...
就是回不去了
Just can't be fixed.